

# **Abhishek Mamdapure**

# **Lead Data Scientist**

An experienced Data Scientist, with a Master's in **Mathematical Modeling and Simulation**, 3+ years of experience and focus on designing and deploying NLP-based models, handling textual big-data, and working with algorithms in the PaaS environment. Currently leading initiatives at Wynum Automation Services in Pune, driving their Large Language Models (LLMs), Graph Neural Networks, and Vector Search based technologies.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

04/2022 – present Pune, India

## Wynum Automation Services Pvt Ltd 🛮

Lead Data Scientist

- Worked directly under the CTO to seamlessly transition **5 key projects** to production within tight deadlines.
- Single-handedly developed a generative-AI-driven voice-based recruiting
  platform and led a team of 4 to create solutions such as embeddings-based
  search engines with FAISS, AI-powered chatbots producing insights, graphs,
  and plots, as well as other predictive models from scratch to address business
  challenges.
- Handled major communication with 3 of the company's largest clients; communicated complex technical concepts to a non-technical audience, including presenting findings and recommendations to senior leadership.
- Currently continuously researching, developing and maintaining scalable data pipelines for collecting, storing, and processing large datasets.
- Mentoring and **training over 6 junior data scientists** on building robust, fault-tolerant intelligent systems and best practices in data science.

07/2020 – 04/2022 Pune, India

#### Wynum Automation Services Pvt Ltd 🛮

Data Science Analyst

- Analyzed large datasets to identify trends, patterns, and relationships.
- Designed and implemented data pipelines to collect, store, and process large datasets.
- Developed dashboards and reports to visualize and communicate data insights to stakeholders.
- Stayed up-to-date with the latest trends and techniques in the field of data analysis.
- Participated in the continuous improvement of data analysis processes and tools.

01/2020 – 07/2020 Bangalore, India

# **Affine Analytics Private Limited**

Data Science Intern

During my tenure at Affine, I was responsible for designing and implementing an NLP system for converting natural language questions into SQL queries for a specific database.

| EDUCATION   |   |  |
|-------------|---|--|
| 2018 – 2020 | M. Tech. Mathematical Modeling and Simulation   |  |
| Pune, India | Savitribai Phule Pune University ☑  |  |
|             | <b>Subjects</b> : Machine Learning, Operations Research, Optimization, Numerical Computing. |  |
| 2012 – 2016 | B.E. Electronics and Telecommunications   |  |

Marathwada Mitra Mandal's College of Engineering, Pune ☑

|                                | SKILLS                    |   |
|--------------------------------|---------------------------|---|
| • Python Programming           | Machine Learning          | • Deep Neural Networks                    |
| • PyTorch                      | • Statistical Analysis    | • Natural Language Processing             |
| • Large Language Models (LLMs) | • Transformers            | • Amazon Web Services (AWS)               |
| • Productionizing Models       | • MongoDB                 | <ul> <li>Customer Segmentation</li> </ul> |
| SDLC and Agile Methodology     | Stakeholder Communication | • Team Management                         |

#### **CERTIFICATES**

**NPTEL - Deep Learning** (Indian Institute of Technology - Kharagpur)

**NPTEL - Practical Machine Learning With Tensorflow** (Indian Institute of Technology - Madras)

### **ORGANIZATIONS**

| 03/2019 – present | Age Of Geeks |
|-------------------|--------------|
| Pune, India       | Volunteer    |

Pune, India

As part of Age Of Geeks, India's largest social-media-driven AI community with over 500,000 members, I was actively involved in organizing and speaking at events. The community is rooted in the belief in India's potential to become a global leader in the technology industry.

| INTERESTS                    |                          |                             |  |  |  |
|------------------------------|--------------------------|-----------------------------|--|--|--|
| • Startups                   | Researching              | • Continuous Learning       |  |  |  |
| • Tech-Community Involvement | Open-Source Contribution | • Al For Good               |  |  |  |
| LANGUAGES                    |                          |                             |  |  |  |
| • English                    | • Hindi                  | <ul> <li>Marathi</li> </ul> |  |  |  |